THERESA MORGAN

UX DESIGNER

DETAILS

ADDRESS

Austin TX

PHONE

830 456 1438

EMAIL

t.morgan106@gmail.com

LINKS

LinkedIn

Portfolio

SKILLS

HTML/CSS/JavaScript

Information Architecture

Interaction Design

Data Analysis

A/B Testing

Figma

Adobe Creative Suite

Creative Problem Solving

Interpersonal Communication Skills

Adaptability

PRESS

2019 "Interview with Theresa Morgan," Savvy Painter Podcast

2016 "21 under 31," Southwest Art Magazine

PROFILE

Outcome-driven UX Designer with 10 years in creative industries.

Highly experienced in quick illustrations and externalizing concepts to demonstrate design thinking and bring alignment to teams. Adept at facilitating creative brainstorming, identifying insights and co-creating data-informed solutions.

Highly motivated, actively seeking opportunities to learn and deepen my understanding of both internal and external stakeholders.

PROJECTS

Lead FE Developer + UX Designer | Walmart

Austin

Dec 2020

Co-created iterative solutions for Walmart's grocery e-commerce flows resulting in 34% faster discover-ability and 45% faster task completion.

Led team in collaboratively coding final mock-ups with Bootstrap and Github.

UX Designer at SEQRPAY (Pre-launch Startup)

Austin

Oct 2020

Designed a branded conversion-driven website within 2 week design sprint.

Unified team's focus for MVP.

Developed materials that resulted in startup placing in pitching competition.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

UI Designer, HelpAction

Austin

Jan 2021 — Present

Working within design system to create interactive elements for non-profit crowdfunding platform.

Visual Artist, Sole Proprietor

Austin

2014 — Present

Developed + led workshops and team building experiences focused on creative collaboration.

Collaborated on 6 mural projects, including a 5 story mural in downtown San Francisco.

Taught over 60 classes and 2 summer camps that I fully organized and implemented.

Participated in live painting events

Sold almost 100 paintings, completed 12 commission projects and participated in 22 shows. Work is in 3 collections.

Art Instructor, Art Plus Academy

Austin

2019 - 2020

Taught weekly lessons, providing live demonstrations, individually tailored lesson plans and facilitated weekly constructive feedback sessions.

AWARDS

1st Place, Techstar Startup Weekend

San Antonio

Dec 2020

Finalist, Austin Design Week

Austin

Nov 2020

Human Relations Award, Dale Carnegie Program

Roundrock

Jan 2018

2nd Place, Annual Artist Competition, Artist Magazine

Online

Apr 2014

EDUCATION

UI/UX Design Bootcamp, University of Texas

Austin

Jun 2020 — Jan 2021

24-week bootcamp dedicated to design principles and best practices.

Attended: HackTX 2020, Austin Design Week, Techstars

BFA - Painting and Illustration, Academy of Art University

San Francisco

Jan 2009 — Dec 2014

5 year undergraduate program focused on technical skills and critical thinking. 5x Award Winner at Annual Spring Show | Valedictorian Nominee

COURSES

Front End Engineer Certificate, Codecademy PRO

Business Skills Certificate, University of Texas

12 week Dale Carnegie Course, Dale Carnegie

Masterclass 7 week Painting Workshop, Jerusalem Studio School

REFERENCES

References available upon request